<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The case of Elizabeth Dutchess of Albemarle, and Christopher Monke Esquire, [brace] appellants.  Against John, Earl of Bath, and others respondents</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1680</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 36 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 4 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2013-12">2013-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B08631</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing C911A</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R173516</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">64551027</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 64551027</idno>
            <idno type="VID">184416</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B08631)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 184416)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2863:23)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The case of Elizabeth Dutchess of Albemarle, and Christopher Monke Esquire, [brace] appellants.  Against John, Earl of Bath, and others respondents</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>4 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London? :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1680]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Imperfect: pages are creased.</note>
                  <note>Place and date of publication suggested by Wing (2nd ed.).</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in: Harvard University. Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Albemarle, Elizabeth Monck, --  Duchess of, 1654-1734 --  Estate --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Albemarle, Christopher Monck, --  Duke of, 1653-1688 --  Estate --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Bath, John Grenville, --  Earl of, 1628-1701.</term>
               <term>Decedents' estates --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2012-06</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-07</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-10</date>
            <label>Colm MacCrossan</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-10</date>
            <label>Colm MacCrossan</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-02</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="legal_account">
            <pb facs="tcp:184416:1"/>
            <head>THE CASE OF <hi>Elizabeth</hi> Dutcheſs of <hi>Albemarle,</hi> and <hi>Chriſtopher Monke</hi> Eſquire, Appellants. AGAINST <hi>John,</hi> Earl of <hi>Bath,</hi> and others Reſpondents</head>
            <p>THE Appellants Bill in the Chancery ſought to be relieved againſt two Deeds of Leaſe and Releaſe mentioned,
<note place="margin">The proceed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ings in Chan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cery, and ſtate of the Caſe.</note> to bear Date the 15 and 16th of <hi>July</hi> 1681: And that the E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtate Real and Perſonal of <hi>Chriſtopher,</hi> late Duke of <hi>Albemarle,</hi> might go according to his Graces laſt Will, Dated the 4th of <hi>July</hi> 1687. And to have an Execution of the ſeveral Truſts in the ſaid Will.</p>
            <p>And the ſaid Earl inſiſted on a Will of the 23d of <hi>Auguſt</hi> 1675, and on the ſaid Deeds as well executed and duly obtained, and ſought thereby wholly to avoid, and render ineffectual the ſaid Laſt Will, tho' the ſame was moſt ſolemnly-made and intended by the ſaid Duke to be the compleat and entire Settlement of all his Eſtate as herein after is mentioned.</p>
            <p>The Court on the 8th <hi>July</hi> 1681,
<note place="margin">Firſt Decree. The Will of 1689, confirm<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed as to the perſonal Eſtate and a Decree for Account accordingly.</note> after four days De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bate <hi>Decreed the Dutcheſs to have her Specifick Legacies, and the perſonal Eſtate to be accounted to Mr.</hi> Monke, <hi>and other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe to be applyed according to the Will of</hi> 1687. Which Decree for the Perſonal Eſtate has never ſince been que<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtioned. And the ſaid Will of 1687, had alſo, before been ſolemnly ſentenced to be a Good Will, and that the Duke intended the ſame ſo to be, by the Court of Delegates. But as to the real Eſtate, before any further direction to be given touching the ſame, the Court did think fit, and ſo order, That a Tryal at Law ſhould be had touching the ſaid Deeds of Leaſe and Releaſe, in ſuch manner as in the ſaid Order is mentioned: and after the ſaid parties were to reſort back to the Court, for their further direction.</p>
            <p>A Tryal was accordingly had,
<note place="margin">Tryal at Law, and the Cauſe again heard.</note> and there happened to to be a Verdict for the Defendants, and afterwards the Cauſe being ſeveral days again debated, before the Lords Commiſſioners, they took further time to conſider thereof. But before they made any final Decree, that Commiſſion was ſuperſeded. And the ſaid Cauſe coming to be fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther heard before the Lord Keeper, ſeveral matters were inſiſted upon, whereby in Equity, to eſtabliſh the ſaid Will of 1687, as the intire Settlement of the ſaid Dukes Eſtate, notwithſtanding the ſaid Deed. His Lordſhip on the 22d of <hi>December</hi> laſt, pronounced a Decree there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in,
<note place="margin">Second Error.</note> to this effect. <hi>That as to the Appellants, ſeveral Claims and Demands to the real Eſtate of the ſaid Duke under the Will of</hi> 1687, <hi>againſt the Deed of</hi> 1681, <hi>their ſaid Bill, ſhould be diſmiſſed,</hi> and did not Relieve the Appellants, as with humble Submiſſion ought to have been done. And therefore they have brought this Appeal, wherein the General queſtion is, <hi>Whether the Deeds of</hi> 16 July 1681, <hi>or the Will of the</hi> 4 July 1687 <hi>in Equity be conſtrued to be the true Settlement of the Duke's Eſtate.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Obſerv.</hi> 1ſt. That in this Decretal Order, as now entred, of all the matters offered and debated in Court, after four days were ſpent herein, there is not any one particularrea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon given for the Judgment of the Court, as is uſual in Caſes of ſo great conſequence: But only in general, That the Court ſaw no Cauſe in Equity to Relieve</p>
            <p n="2">2dly. That the Lord Keeper and Judges did lay great ſtreſs on the Verdict, and that there had been no motion for a new Tryal And that ſo the Deeds muſt be now ſup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſed to be taken as good Deeds: Which 'tis humbly ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ped will not now be of weight; <hi>For there was nothing inſiſted on at the Tryal but the Fact only.</hi> And ſo the Verdict is or ought to be of no further Evidence, than that the Duke ſealed the Deed. And there was no motion for a new Try<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>al: Not becauſe the Appellants were ſatisfied with that Verdict, or had, as they conceived, any reaſon ſo to be. But becauſe it was and is conceived, That ſuppoſing the Duke did Execute ſuch Deeds, there are matters in Equi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty ariſing out of the Deeds themſelves, and otherwiſe relating thereto, ſufficient to ſet the ſame aſide, or ren<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der the ſame ineffectual. Firſt, <hi>Either as unduly obtained,</hi> Secondly, <hi>Or as unduly ſecreted and concealed from the Duke. Or</hi> Thirdly, <hi>as in Equity revoked by the laſt Will of</hi> 1687. <hi>Or</hi> Fourthly, <hi>as a Truſt reſulting for the Duke, whereby this his laſt Will of</hi> 1687, <hi>may have its full effect, and operation.</hi> But before theſe Points are ſeverally con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſidered, it is neceſſary to ſee what the Will and Deeds are; and under what circumſtances they ſtand,</p>
            <p>And were the Fact, the direct queſtion at preſent, it would be remembred and is proved:
<note place="margin">Some of the Evidence as to the Fact of the Deed.</note> 
               <hi>That when the Deeds were firſt produced by the Earl, they were read by his Lordſhip's own Counſel, to be dated, the Leaſe the</hi> 15 July 1681, <hi>and the Releaſe the</hi> 16 July 1682, <hi>at which great no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tice was taken, and with much difficulty Mr.</hi> Bowes <hi>and Mr.</hi> Buttler <hi>got the Earle's leave to look on the ſame, and obſerved the Leaſe to be</hi> 1682, <hi>as the ſame had been read, and with thoſe two Witneſſes concur, the Lord</hi> Cheney <hi>Mr.</hi> Cheney, <hi>and Dr.</hi> Barwick, <hi>and thereof Mr.</hi> Bowes, <hi>and by Lord</hi> Cheney<hi>'s direction, Mr.</hi> Cheney <hi>then entred ſeveral Memorandums in writing: And on ſight of the Deed of Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leaſe, there appeares now a plain Razure, both in the Year of the King, and in the Year of our Lord but in no other word throughout the whole Deed, for ought appeared.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Now the difference was very material, not only becauſe if the Releaſe were 1682 <hi>(as theſe five Gentlemen ſay it was),</hi> it would not only be void at Law (the Leaſe being determined) but Sir <hi>William Jones,</hi> whoſe name is En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dorſed as a Witneſs, was dead in <hi>July</hi> 1682.</p>
            <p>As alſo, <hi>That it now appears to have been Engroſſed at the Earls Houſe, at St.</hi> James<hi>'s, and by his direction, by one</hi> Thompſon, <hi>who hath been the Earls Scrivener for theſe thirty Years.</hi> Whereas the Earl by his Anſwer ſays, <hi>he knows not who Engroſſed it: But it being of great moment and ſecrecy, was all committed to the Care and Conduct of Sir</hi> William Jones.</p>
            <p>And alſo, that <hi>Thompſon</hi> on his firſt Examination ſwore, <hi>That in</hi> 1687 <hi>he Ingroſſed for the ſaid Earl a Deed of the ſame purport, as this,</hi> (whereas this Deed is dated 1681) <hi>and remembers not that ever he Engroſſed any other.</hi> But when he is afterwards produced by the Earl, then there is ſhewn to him a Parchment prepared to be, but never Executed by the Dake. And this he ſays, is what he Engroſſed for the Earl in 1687, (as is ſaid, prepared in 1687) both as to the Power of Revocation, and eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry thing elſe <hi>is the ſame in words with the Deed of</hi> 1681, ſaving only the laſt Covenant not to revoke the Will of 1675 And <hi>Thompſon</hi> ſays, <hi>he thought it had been Exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cuted in</hi> 1687, and this done without the Duke's dire<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctions, or any occaſion for the ſame: for if the Duke had before Executed the other, <hi>and had it in his Cuſtody, (as is ſaid by the Earl in his Anſwer)</hi> what need was there thereof?</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:184416:2"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" resp="#OXF" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="2" facs="tcp:184416:3"/>
            <p>As alſo, <hi>That after</hi> July 1681. <hi>the Earl was adviſing with my Lord Preſident how he might procure a Settlement from the Duke.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>As alſo, <hi>That the Seal of the Duke's Coat of Arms, which is upon this Deed, was cut by Mr.</hi> Eaſt, <hi>for the Earl of</hi> Bath, <hi>and the Earl paid him for that</hi> 3 l. 10 s. <hi>and alſo for another ſmall Seal of his own Arms at the ſame time. And the ſaid Mr.</hi> Eaſt <hi>ſtill hath the impreſſion of both Seals, which he kept in ſoft Wax.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>As alſo, <hi>How many Witneſſes, well acquainted with the Hand-writing of the Duke, and Sir</hi> William Jones, <hi>and Sir</hi> John Coppleſton, <hi>have ſworn, they do not believe theſe to be ſo.</hi> With other Evidence offered on that Subject, of the Fact.</p>
            <p>But more immediately towards the Points of Equity, it is to be conſidered,</p>
            <q> That the Will of 1687.
<note place="margin">Contents of the Will of 4 <hi>July</hi> 1687.</note> contains a fair, compleat, and honourable Settlement of all the Real and Perſonal Eſtate; ſome part to the Dutcheſs for Life, ſome part to his Friends and Relations, and Legacies to others of them, and particularly to <hi>Bevil Greenvill,</hi> younger Son of the Earl of <hi>Bath,</hi> Lands worth 30000 <hi>l.</hi> and to Sir <hi>Walter Clargis,</hi> after the death of the Dutcheſs, Lands, to the value of 1500 <hi>l. per annum,</hi> or thereabouts. It deviſes a Monument not exceeding 5000 <hi>l.</hi> to be ere<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cted for himſelf, his Father, and his Mother; and de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viſes Alms-houſes to be built, and a Charity of 200 <hi>l. per annum</hi> to Twenty poor Widows, purſuant to the intention of his Mother, and provides well for the payment of his Debts, and leaves the inheritance of the greateſt part of his Eſtate to his Couſin Col. <hi>Tho. Monke,</hi> and his Sons in Tail-Male, with Remainder to his Couſin Col. <hi>Henry Monke</hi> in <hi>Ireland</hi> and his Sons, with other Remainders over; and contains his humble Requeſt to His Majeſty, in memory of his Father, and his own Services, to create the ſaid Col. <hi>Tho. Monke</hi> (the Appellant <hi>Monk</hi>'s Father) Baron <hi>Monke</hi> of <hi>Pothe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ridge,</hi> and to the Heirs Males of his Body; ſo that the Name of <hi>Monke,</hi> and his Eſtate, may to Poſterity re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>main together.</q>
            <p>And becauſe the Earl, by his Anſwer, has made his Caſe, and accordingly the Court have ſeemed to take it highly reflecting on the Duke's Honour, That <hi>the Duke, at the very time of making the Will of</hi> 1687. <hi>intended the ſame ſhould be void, and ſignifie nothing, and the Deed ſtand, and that the Duke ſent him to Counſel, to adviſe, Whether the Deed could be avoided by a Will? and he told him, It would not:</hi> Wherewith the Duke ſeemed well pleaſed. It is there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore to be ſeen what Steps the Duke made about it; and the whole may be put upon that iſſue, <hi>Whether the Duke in this Caſe was guilty of ſo much Folly, Prevarication, and Diſſimu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lation towards GOD and the King, his Wife and Relations, when he had no ſort of Benefit or Temptation upon him ſo to do;</hi> as not really <hi>to intend that to be effectually his Will which coſt him ſo much care and pains, and which was ſo ſolemnly perfected,</hi> as will appear.</p>
            <p>The Proofs of the Sincerity of his Intentions,
<note place="margin">Prooſs of the Sincerity of the ſaid Duke's Intentions, by the laſt Will of 87. ſome of them prece<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dent, ſome of them conco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitant, and o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers ſubſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quent.</note> and the Freedom of his Mind, are <hi>ſome of them precedent to the Will,</hi> ſome of them <hi>concomitant,</hi> and others of them <hi>ſubſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quent.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Sir <hi>Henry Bellaſis</hi> and Sir <hi>Robert Clayton</hi> ſwear the Duke's declaring his Intentions precedent before the Will prepared, who he intended to give Col. <hi>Monke</hi> in <hi>Holland</hi> the beſt part of the Eſtate, and how he intended to ſetle the ſame. And Sir <hi>Robert Clayton,</hi> That the Duke ſent him for the Lord Chief-Juſtice <hi>Pollexfen</hi> to draw it; and in order thereto, ſent to the Earl of <hi>Bath</hi> for a former Will of his he had made: Which accordingly the Earl of <hi>Bath</hi> confeſſeth he gave him in <hi>December</hi> 1686.</p>
            <p>The L. Chief-Juſtice <hi>Pollexfen</hi> ſwears, <q rend="inline">He went with Sir <hi>Robert Clayton,</hi> and drew the Will, by Directions and Inſtructions from the Duke's own Mouth, and was often with him about it, and that ſeveral Alterations were by the Duke's Order made in it, and that the Matter was long tranſacting and ſetling, and that he never ſaw any man more earneſt to have his Will well done, and according to his mind; and when he had fi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſhed the Draught, he read it to the Duke, and after ſome amendments again thereupon made by the Duke's directions, he was deſired by his Grace to get his Clerk to engroſs it, leaving blanks for the Executors Names; and the Duke deſired him to be one of his Executors, to which he <hi>conſented;</hi> and, that Sir <hi>Thomas Stringer</hi> was ſome of the times preſent with the Duke and him about it. That it was publiſhed at Sir <hi>Robert Clayton</hi>'s, after the Duke had there Executed the Deeds of the Mannors of <hi>Dalby</hi> and <hi>Broughton</hi> to Lord <hi>Jefferies,</hi> in the <hi>preſence of Three Witneſſes, and of Sir</hi> Tho. Stringer, <hi>who did not ſubſcribe, becauſe he was one of the Executors.</hi> And for the greater ſolemnity, the Duke hath to Three ſeveral parts, each containing 19 ſheets of Paper, and to every ſheet of each part ſubſcribed his Name, and affixed his Seal, and cauſed the Witneſſes likewiſe to ſubſcribe their Names to each ſheet, and afterwards ſealed them under three ſeveral Covers, and endorſed on all the Covers, with his own Hand, theſe words, <hi>My Will, the</hi> 4th <hi>July,</hi> 1687. He kept them all in his own cuſtody till his going to <hi>Jamaica,</hi> and then delivered one of them to the Lady <hi>Eliz. Pierpoint,</hi> to be given to the Dutcheſs of <hi>Newcaſtle;</hi> another of them he gave to the ſaid Col. <hi>Monke,</hi> whom he had ſent for from <hi>Holland</hi> for that purpoſe, and writ to his preſent Majeſty, then Prince, to procure him Leave to come, and did treat him, his Wife and Son, with Lodgings and Dyet in <hi>Newcaſtle-Houſe,</hi> with himſelf, and made him a Preſent of 3<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>0 <hi>l.</hi> for his Expences in coming over. The third part thereof he carried with him to <hi>Jamaica,</hi> where about a fortnight before his Death he re-publiſhed the ſame, and kept it in his ſtrong Box, amongſt things of the greateſt value to him, and directed the Keys there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of to be given to his Wife, in caſe he relapſed and there dyed</q>
            </p>
            <p>Beſides all theſe Solemnities,
<note place="margin">Letters be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tween the L. of <hi>Bath,</hi> the Duke, and the Truſtees, about <hi>Monke,</hi> in con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>firmation of his Laſt Will.</note> and the great care and concern of the Duke, in his ſaid Will, for his Kinſman Col. <hi>Monk;</hi> when afterwards the Duke in <hi>Jamaica</hi> heard of the death of the ſaid Col. <hi>Monke,</hi> he put himſelf and Family into Mourning. And not only the Duke, but alſo the Earl of <hi>Bath,</hi> Sir <hi>Walter Cla<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>gis,</hi> Sir <hi>Tho. Stringer,</hi> and the reſt of the <hi>Duke</hi>'s Truſtees, looked on the Appellant <hi>Chriſtopher Monke,</hi> eldeſt Son of the ſaid Colonel, as the perſon who would have the <hi>Duke</hi>'s Eſtate in caſe of his death: Which appears by Letters even <hi>under the Earl of</hi> Bath<hi>'s and others of the Truſtees Hands,</hi> recommending it to the <hi>Duke,</hi> on the death of Col. <hi>Monke; That ſince his Grace had thought fit to promote that Branch of his Family (how remote ſoever) into ſo great a ſhare of his Favour, there ſhould be ſomething done towards the breeding up the Children, to make them appear in the World anſwerable to that figure which his Grace had deſigned they ſhould one day make in it.</hi> Such is the one of the Letters ſigned by the Earl of <hi>Bath.</hi> And divers other Letters there are to the ſame effect, as alſo from the <hi>Duke,</hi> in Anſwer, directing, <hi>That the Earl of</hi> Bath <hi>and Truſtees ſhould forthwith ſend into</hi> Hol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land <hi>for the Appellant</hi> Chriſtopher, <hi>and that Care be taken of him, to have him well educated; That he may</hi> (as the words of the Letter go) <hi>receive ſuch improvement as is pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>per for what I have already deſigned him; and therefore think it convenient, that he be put under the Tuition of Monſ.</hi> Faubert; <hi>and that particular Care be taken to ſee it done, and give me an Account, from time to time, how he proceeds in his Studies.</hi> And accordingly the Truſtees, and particularly the Earl of <hi>Bath,</hi> who took upon him the greateſt Trou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble thereof, agreed for him, and a Servant with him, to be at Monſieur <hi>Faubert</hi>'s, at above 200 <hi>l. per annum</hi> Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pence; and the Earl of <hi>Bath</hi> often viſited him there. <hi>Whereas if this Will of</hi> 1687. <hi>be not the Real Will and Setle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of the ſaid Duke, (but that the Deed of</hi> 1681. <hi>ſhould ſtand) there's nothing at all given to the Appellant Mr.</hi> Monke, <hi>to make a Figure, or bear any Character, as the Letters go.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The Earl of <hi>Bath,</hi> by his Anſwer,
<note place="margin">The Earl's Anſwer about <hi>Faubert</hi>'s.</note> goes to explain all this, and ſays, That <hi>Faubert</hi>'s was the place where the <hi>Duke</hi> uſed to breed his Pages to Fencing and Riding; and has alſo proved it by a Witneſs; but he hath not ſhewed, That ſuch Expreſſions as are in the Letters were uſual with the <hi>Duke</hi> or <hi>himſelf,</hi> in relation to the Pages, <hi>viz. What Figures they were to make, and what Characters they were to bear one day in the World, and how many Pages the Duke did breed with a Servant at ſuch expence, and how many Viſits the Earl did ever make the Pages, as he uſed to do Mr.</hi> Monke, <hi>and how many of the Pages were to proceed in their Studies there as the Duke directsr Mr.</hi> Monke <hi>ſhould do.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And as to the pretended Importunities of the Dutcheſs to obtain the Laſt Will, it is fully anſwered.</p>
            <p>The <hi>Duke</hi> and <hi>Dutcheſs</hi> always lived well together;
<note place="margin">Dutcheſs's pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tended Impor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tunities anſwe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red.</note> neither was it her Intereſt in any ſort to ſet up Mr. <hi>Monke,</hi> for Col. <hi>Monke</hi> was much a Stranger, in compa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſon of the Earl of <hi>Bath,</hi> who tells by his Anſwer how many ways he had obliged her. Beſides, this Deed (if <hi>Dalby</hi> and <hi>Broughton</hi> had not been ſince ſold) ſetles very near as much Land on her as the Laſt Will.</p>
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:184416:3"/>
            <p>And the Lord Ch. Juſt. <hi>Pollexfen</hi> ſwears, <hi>he uſed to be with the Duke in the mornings, and that he acted, freely and was in a very fit condition to make a Will.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And Mr. <hi>Bowes</hi> ſwears he recommended it to the Duke, inſtead of the uſe of the Goods for Life, to give her the property of them, <hi>and that he refuſed.</hi> As alſo, denyed to give her the Inheritance of that which had been her Fathers Eſtate at <hi>Grindon,</hi> which ſhews the litlte influence ſhe had: And likewiſe that the Duke expelled the Will to be good. But yet his eſteem for her appears in that, in the Will produced by the Earl of <hi>Bath,</hi> and in a Will of 1673, and in all his Wills, he named her ſole Guardian of all his Children, if he had any.</p>
            <p>And it is further here to be conſidered, That the Duke had too much Courage to do any thing through fear, or importunity; and more Honour than ſo to diſſemble either with the Earl, or Colonel <hi>Monke:</hi> but the natu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral conſtruction which ſaves the Duke's Honour, is, <hi>That in</hi> 1675 <hi>he might intend ſome part of his Eſtate to the Earl of</hi> Bath. <hi>But in</hi> 1687, <hi>when Colonel</hi> Monke<hi>'s great credit in the Army had more endeared him to the Duke, and he had hope<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful Sons, and the Eldeſt Son his Godſon, and the Duke as by the Will is expreſſed, deſiring that the great part of his Eſtate ſhould continue in his own name, really intended it for Mr</hi> Monke <hi>and his Sons, &amp;c. and yet was bountiful alſo to the Earl of</hi> Bath<hi>'s Son, as aforeſaid,</hi> and <hi>he might well in ſo many years alter his intention.</hi> And as to the Deed in 1681.</p>
            <p>Now that this Deed muſt have ſome way by Surpriſe,
<note place="margin">Surprixe in Reference to the Deed of 1681.</note> or other undue means, have been impoſed upon the Duke, appears by the circumſtances that attend it, and from the face of the Deed it ſelf: <hi>There's not the leaſt proof offered, that the Duke ever gave any directions for it, or read, or heard one word of it read; nor that ever there was any Copy or Counterpart.</hi> And upon reading thereof, <hi>it appears in very unuſual manner and expreſſions, to labour ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>treamly to make a ſhew of a Conſideration.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And then for the Subſtance thereof, <hi>It is abſolutely in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>conſiſtent with it ſelf.</hi> It recites a Will of the 23d of <hi>Auguſt</hi> 1675 (which the Earl of <hi>Bath</hi> ſays, is the Will the Duke took from him in 1686): and it miſrecites ſeve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral things of it; <hi>Then it ſays, it is intended thereby to Corroborate and Confirm the Will,</hi> and yet entirely revokes and contradicts it, and limits the <hi>Eſtate to different uſes,</hi> ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cept only the Mannor of <hi>Midgham</hi> and <hi>Tile-Mills,</hi> which only are to the ſame uſes: But then this Deviſe, in which they only agree, is written on the Margent of the Will, in the <hi>Earl of</hi> Bath<hi>'s own Hand: but by what Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der or Authority from the Duke doth not appear.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And here it is alſo to be noted, That the Deviſe to the Earl of <hi>Bath</hi> and his Heirs, is on the ſixth Sheet of this Will of 1675, and that this ſixth Sheet of this Will is of a different Paper, different Hand-writing, and a different Seal from all the reſt of the Sheets of the Will.</p>
            <p>The Will of 1675,
<note place="margin">Further in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtances of Sur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prize.</note> gave all the Dukes Eſtate to his own Daughters in caſe he had any, before the Earl, or his Sons or Daughters, as good reaſon there was. But the Deed of 1681 limits the Eſtate in <hi>Eſſex</hi> and <hi>Lan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>caſhire,</hi> &amp;c. to the amount of 5000 <hi>l.</hi> a Year, ſo as the ſame would go to the Earl of <hi>Bath</hi> and his Daughters before the Dukes own Daughters. Which ſeemed not Anſwered, in ſaying that the Duke might expect the Earl would be created Duke of <hi>Albemarle,</hi> and do it for his ſupport, but certainly the Earl's Daughters were not to be Dukes, <hi>and yet they would by the Deed carry the Eſtate from the Duke's Daughters.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Part of the occaſion of making the Deed, the Earl ſays by his Pleadings, was to make Proviſion for younger Sons, in which his Marriage-Settlement was defective. And yet, the Lands ſettled by this Deed of 1681, for ſuch Younger Sons are <hi>Redriſſe, Norton, Diſney,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>which by the Marriage-Settlement were ſettled on the Duke's Eldeſt Son.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Then the extraordinary nature of the Power of Revo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cation, That it <hi>muſt be done in the preſence of ſix Witneſſes, and three of them Peers,</hi> whereby the Duke put himſelf under great <hi>incapacities;</hi> ſome times it might be impoſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble for him to get three Peers, as it was in <hi>Jamaica;</hi> And if he had them, <hi>he was in their power whether they would be Witneſſes or no.</hi> And thereafter comes the Covenant, <hi>not to Revoke or alter the Will of</hi> 1675, which by that Deed was <hi>actually Revoked,</hi> as aforeſaid.</p>
            <p>Nor had the Duke himſelf any power by the Deed to make Leaſes: and yet all this muſt be kept from the knowledge of the Duke, and ſo he knew not how exactly to purſue it.</p>
            <p>But the Earl <hi>Bath</hi> by his Anſwer,
<note place="margin">The Earl of <hi>Bath</hi>'s Anſwer about the In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>groſſing the Deed, and Sir <hi>W. Jones.</hi>
               </note> to give the greater credit to the Deed, ſays, <hi>That he knows not who Engroſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed it, but it was committed all to the Care and Conduct of Sir</hi> William Jones, <hi>and he came to be a Witneſs to it, at</hi> Al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bemarle-<hi>Houſe, and believes Sir</hi> William Jones <hi>read it to him before it came to be perfected, and that the Duke was often with him about it, after the time that Sir</hi> Tho. Stringer <hi>had prepared the Draught, but was not to be truſted with the know<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledge of the Execution of it.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Now when the Court obſerved <hi>the ſtrange frame of the Deed, and the many Inconſiſtencies, Improprieties, and Coni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tradctions therein.</hi> They declared, <hi>That they did not believe that ever Sir</hi> William Jones <hi>drew the ſaid Deed, only was conſulted upon the Proviſoe,</hi> which ſeems not to conſiſt with the Earls Anſwer, <hi>which ſays, that the Care and Conduct of the wholewas committed to Sir</hi> W. Jones. And it now fully ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pears, <hi>That Sir</hi> William Jones <hi>has no hand in the Engroſſing thereof; but it was done by</hi> Thompſon <hi>at the Earls Houſe, as aforeſaid.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And the great Secrecy, <hi>not only in the obtaining,
<note place="margin">Concealment.</note> but concealing thereof appears,</hi> in that it muſt not be known to the Duke of <hi>Newcaſtle,</hi> or any of the Truſtees therein; nor to Sir <hi>Walter Clarges,</hi> who has an Eſtate thereby, and was the Duke's intimate Friend and near Relation; nor to Sir <hi>Thomas Stringer,</hi> who, it is ſaid, drew the Draught. But yet the Earl's Anſwer confeſſeth he was not to know of the Execution thereof, leſt he ſhould tell the Dutcheſs, tho ſhe hath ſo great an Eſtate thereby, that it was her intereſt to eſpouſe it, and thank the Earl for his great kindneſs expreſſed in his Anſwer, by prevai<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling with the Duke to make her Eſtate thereby ſo much better than it was before.</p>
            <p>Then that the Duke <hi>with the privity of the Earl of</hi> Bath, ſold <hi>Dalby</hi> and <hi>Broughton</hi> to the Lord <hi>Jefferys,</hi> as alſo <hi>Bitchfield</hi> before, without the leaſt notice either by the Duke, or the Earl of any ſuch Deed: And made many Leaſes without fines, which he had thereby no power given him to do. And alſo made divers voluntary Conveyances, and Grants of Rent Charges of 100 <hi>l. per annum,</hi> to one, &amp; other voluntary Annuities to his Friends and Servants, which would be avoided by the Deed. And all the ſubſequent acts of the Duke ſo inconſiſtent therewith, That it is next to impoſſibility to think that the Duke ſhould have done the ſame, and yet be acquain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted with the ſaid Deed.</p>
            <p>And the Lord Ch. Juſt. <hi>Pollexfen,</hi> and Sir <hi>Robert Clayton</hi> ſay, that they enquired on the ſaid occaſions, what ſet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tlement the Duke had made, and could hear of none, but the Marriage-Settlement in 1669. Beſides, Mr. <hi>Courtney</hi> ſays, it was under great Injunctions of Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>crecy, the Earl ſpoke to him about it. And the Earl of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fers no proof that it was ever ſeen in the Duke's Cuſtody, or delivered to him by the Duke, from the time of the firſt Execution thereof, only ſays the Duke gave it to him in his Bed-chamber, and no body preſent, unleſs ſome body might be behind the Bed. And there is nothing does more clearly prove the Concealment of the Deed from the Duke, than his great Care about his laſt Will in 1687.</p>
            <p>However,
<note place="margin">Third General Head: it is in Equity Revo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ked.</note> though the Power of Revocation be not lit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terally purſued, ſo as to be a Revocation in ſtrictneſs at Common Law; <hi>yet in Equity under theſe circumſtances, the ſaid laſt Will of</hi> 1687, <hi>ought to be adjudged a Revocati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on thereof, as made purſuant to the intent of that power thereby reſerved to the Duke:</hi> The Witneſſes according to the Letter of the Power ought to be ſix, and three of them to be Peers, <hi>but they need not all be preſent at the ſame time,</hi> nor <hi>all to ſubſcribe their names.</hi> Now though there were only three Witneſſes preſent at firſt, yet there were many more than ſix, to whom the Duke af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terwards publiſhed it here and in <hi>Jamaica: So that there wants neither number nor credibility of Witneſſes, only qua<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lity for three of them,</hi> which 'tis hoped will be no ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jection in this Caſe; when it was not poſſible, when he laſt publiſhed the Will in <hi>Jamaica,</hi> to have it.</p>
            <p>But the Court would not allow this in <hi>Jamaica</hi> to be a Publication, <hi>being accidental,</hi> though it was plain in the proof, <hi>That the Duke took it then in his hand, and told the Witneſſes it was his Will, and directed the Keys of his ſtrong Box, where it was kept, to be given to the Dutcheſs if he dyed:</hi> And the more accidental it was, the more it ſhewes the <hi>Innocency and Sincerity</hi> of the Duke's intentions.</p>
            <pb n="4" facs="tcp:184416:4"/>
            <p>It does appear upon the Face,
<note place="margin">
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>ching the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>t of Truſt.</note> and by the expreſs words of the Deed, that the Eſtate limited to the Earl, is upon this ſpecial Truſt and Confidence, <q rend="inline">That he ſhall ſell ſo much of the Lands as ſhall fully and honeſtly pay all the Duke's Juſt Debts, and Legacies, and Funeral Charges, as much as the Perſonal Eſtate comes ſhort in the Pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment thereof by his Executors in his ſaid Will mentio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ned. </q>
            </p>
            <p>So that, according to this very <hi>Deed,</hi> whatſoever <hi>Debts</hi> the <hi>Duke</hi> had contracted, or ſhould contract, though not in the preſence of Six Witneſſes, and tho' they were to the full value of the ſaid Eſtate, the Earl muſt, by the Letter of the Truſt, ſell the Eſtate to pay the ſame; and ſo muſt he have done to ſatisfie all the Deviſes and Legacies, which the <hi>Duke</hi> at his pleaſure ſhould make or give by any other Will, were it not for the Addition of thoſe Five Words, <hi>viz. (In his ſaid Will mentioned.)</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Now, when one of the chief Conſiderations of the ſaid <hi>Deed</hi> is expreſſed, <hi>to corroborate that Will of</hi> 1675. <hi>and make good thoſe Legacies given thereby;</hi> and that the Laſt Will does ſo plainly revoke that Will; and that the Earl by reaſon thereof would now have the whole without paying the Legacies; What more juſt conſtruction, than that this <hi>Deed,</hi>
               <note place="margin">Reaſonable Conſtruction of the Deed.</note> as the Caſe was in <hi>Dyer's Reports,</hi> ſhould be <hi>conſtructed, quaſi</hi> a Will: And <hi>that there was a Truſt for the ſaid Duke, who might have charged it to the full value;</hi> and <hi>that thereupon the Laſt Will of the firſt and laſt Owner of the Eſtate may not be fruſtrated.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Nay, by ſuch Conſtruction ſeveral of the chief Ends pretended even of the <hi>Deed,</hi> will be alſo anſwered; for, <hi>the Deſcent to the Poſterity of a Regicide,</hi> as alſo <hi>the Heir of any other perſon ſetting up any Counterfeit or Surreptitious Will,</hi> which are intended to be obviated by the <hi>Deed,</hi> will be as well this way prevented, as they are by the <hi>Deed,</hi> or any other Conſtruction. <hi>And the rather alſo ought ſuch Conſtru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction to be made, for that in the Draught which is produced as a Support of the Deed, juſt after the ſaid five reſtrictive words,</hi> viz. (In my ſaid Will mentioned) <hi>there appears ſo much of that ſheet as would contain two lines hath been cut away from the bottom, where the ſaid five words end: And by the remaining Heads of the Letters it appears, there was another line writ be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore it was cut, which might very well be to pay his Debts and the Legacies in the ſaid Will mentioned</hi> (or in any other Wri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting to be made or appointed). <hi>And if the words had been ſo, they will not deny, but that the Laſt Will would have had effect thereon.</hi>
            </p>
            <q>NB. <hi>This cutting off the under part of the Draught in this material place was never Obſerved till the Laſt Hearing; and till a good account be given, how the words came to be cut, they ſhould be preſumed to be for the Appellant's Advantage.</hi>
            </q>
            <p>Now, for the Privy-Seal which the Earl hath, promi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſing, that the King would create him <hi>Duke</hi> of <hi>Albemarle,</hi> and alſo give him that part of <hi>Theobald</hi>'s which was to revert to the Crown,
<note place="margin">Anſwer about the Privy-Seal, and the old and late Duke their Services &amp; Friendſhip.</note> and is ſaid to be got at the inſtance of <hi>George</hi> Duke of <hi>Albemarle,</hi> in caſe his Iſſue Male fai<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>led.</p>
            <p>It is plainly anſwered, That both thoſe were things entirely the King's, but that the <hi>Duke</hi> never intended him any of his Eſtate. He made a Setlement on his <hi>Death-bed</hi> of all his Eſtate, and alſo before had made his ſaid Will, and was ſo far from giving the ſaid Earl any part of his Eſtate, that he did not ſo much as Name him a Truſtee in either of them; and by his Will appointed nine Guardians of his Son, but the Earl of <hi>Bath</hi> none of them; and, That it was not Duke <hi>Chriſtopher</hi>'s conſtant Intention, appears by a Will of his made in 1673. whereby the bulk of his Eſtate is divided amongſt his other Relations, and nothing given to the Earl of <hi>Bath,</hi> but a ſmall Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mainder after an <gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>erril Greenvill.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And for his <hi>Relation, Friendſhip,</hi> and <hi>Services,</hi> All that may be, without his having the Eſtate, and the Friend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip and Services as is believed, were fully returned; and if they were not, the Duke remembred them ſufficiently by the Laſt Will, in the ſaid Deviſe to his ſaid Son.</p>
            <p>As to Col. <hi>Monke</hi> deceaſed,
<note place="margin">About Colonel <hi>Monke.</hi>
               </note> who (now he is not to ſpeak for himſelf) has been greatly diſparaged, he was publickly known to be a Gentleman of great Worth and Honour, and as ſuch was raiſed in his Profeſſion. He had the advantage of the Earl, by being of the Duke's name, for whom, and for his Name, the Duke expreſſed great Regard and Concern; and on all occaſions in Company, and by Letters and otherwiſe, the Duke called and treated him as his Relation, and one of the Friends he loved beſt, which is Reaſon ſufficient for what he did.</p>
            <q> 
               <hi>Laſtly,</hi> It is to be noted,
<note place="margin">Court declared ſeveral things myſterious, and not to be underſtood.</note> That though there be a Decree againſt the Appellants, yet in the giving their Opinions of the ſaid Matters, as to the Stories of <hi>Thompſon,</hi> and ſome other things, <hi>it was declared on the Bench, They were ſo myſterious, they could not be underſtood.</hi> And therefore it was by another on the <hi>Bench</hi> declared, He would leave ſeveral things out of the Caſe as myſte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rious, and to that effect. But it is with humble ſub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſion offered to conſideration, <hi>Whether the Reaſon and Argument be not better, That they ought therefore to be brought into the Caſe, and that the Deed ought therefore to be ſet aſide;</hi> conſidering that the Earl of <hi>Bath,</hi> who pioduces it, was all along privy, as he ſays, to every thing of it, and not as a Stranger thereto.</q>
            <p>For all which Reaſons the Appellants humbly hape their Lordſhips will Order the ſaid Decree to be Reverſed, and the Appellants relieved, and that the ſaid Laſt Will, ſo ſolemnly made, as aforeſaid, may be Eſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bliſhed, as the Settlement of the Duke's Eſtate as he intended the ſame.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:184416:4"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
